Tomin Sahu

- **#** 17/12/1998
- **** 7898379442
- **■** tominsahu321@gmail.com
- Current location: Jewartala Road (C.G.)491771, India
- **b** Unmarried

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have gained 1 year and 4 months of experience working in a challenging and creative environment, effectively contributing towards the organization's goals. I am now seeking to join an organization that not only supports my professional and personal growth but also allows me to contribute to the company's development. I am eager to engage in opportunities that align with the company's goals and drive its continued success.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

01/2024 – present Raipur, India

- Railworld India Pvt Ltd
 Proficient in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for building responsive websites
- Skilled in using frameworks like React dynamic user interfaces
- Familiarity with Bootstrap and Materialize CSS for rapid development
- Proficient in basic Git and GitHub usage for managing code versions and collaborating on front-end development projects effectively

 Junior Engineer
 03/2022 - 07/2023

 NSEIT Pvt Ltd
 Mumbai, India

- As a Junior Engineer, I was providing support to the client to access servers from the remote location
- I have experienced working with Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) and deployment of VPC
- I have created linux servers using EC2 service also worked on Snapshots, Life Cycle Manager and AMI
- I am proficient in working with Simple Storage Services (S3)
- I have expertise in creating IAM users and configuring appropriate permissions for security purposes
- I have hands-on experience with CloudTrail, Trusted Advisor, and AWS Inspector
- I have created CloudWatch Dashboards and set up alarms for notifications
- Established Connectivity between source and destination servers
- I am skilled on Cost Explorer and Billing Dashboard to analyze service costs
- Knowledge about Site24×7 and FreshService portal and ITServiceDesk
- Client Interaction in Project
- Additionally, I am proficient in using MS Excel and MS Word

PROJECT

My Portfolio

I have created my portfolio, where I have included my experiences, projects, qualifications and other activities.I developed this portfolio to enhance my skills and gain practical experience in using programming languages for real websites.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, MySQL, Python, Git & GitHub, Figma
- I have acquired a good knowledge in AWS Cloud Computing including EC2, IAM, S3, Route53, Load Balancer, Autoscaling, VPC Peering, Eventbridge, SNS, CloudFront, Site to Site VPN
- Familiar with Windows (7,8,10 and 11) and Linux (RHEL, Amazon Linux 2, Ubuntu)
- Installation of Windows and Linux server operating system
- Installation of IIS, Telnet, DHCP, DNS services on windows server
- Add client server to Domain
- MS Word, PowerPoint, MS Excel
- Good knowledge of Computer Hardware and Networking

EDUCATION

07/2020 - 09/2022 Durg, India

Q CERTIFICATION / TRAINING

- ReactJS for Beginners, by simplilearn SkillUP
- CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Web development Course, by Udemy
- Got "C" certificate in "National Cadet Corps"
- Got certificate in "Junior Red

Cross"

 Actively participated in Sports,
 Speech Competition and Drawing Competition

LANGUAGES

Hindi, English

SOFT SKILLS

- Learning Attitude
- Good Communication Skills
- Problem Solving Skills
- Good Time Management Skills
- Positive Attitude
- Active Listener

S INTERESTS

Learning about new technologies and Internet Surfing, Visiting different places and making new friends. I mainly prefer to do Yoga and Exercise in my daily routine and also like Dance.

DECLARATION

I hereby acknowledge and authenticate that all the information mentioned in this document is accurate and correct in every aspect.